Kestel Castle.
People of Kestel, listen to me!
They have oppressed us for years!
They made us bleed! We
won't step back anymore!
O noble people of Byzantine! No defense!
We'll attack with all our strength!
We'll eradicate the Muslims in these
lands as if they had never existed!
Hold on, brave men! We
won't give up no matter what!
As you see, they aren't invincible.
We aren't invincible but we'll never give up!
I swear I will kill you all.
I'll be your death, Lord!
Can you speak like this when
you are skinned out, Mehmed?
Soldiers, whip!
You think you can scare us? Come on, hit me!
Come on, warriors! Hang on!
Allah is the greatest!
Hit!
-Allah is the greatest!
-Hit them to kill!
Beg, son of Osman. If you beg,
...I may finish this torture.
You treacherous dog!
I'd rather be eaten by birds...
...than begging you! Come on, hit!
Hit! Listen to Orhan. Hit harder!
Hold on, my warriors!
Orhan isn't very smart.
But you and I can be friends.
I will show you who the
enemy and the friend are, Lord!
-Hit!
-I will take your filthy life out.
-Just wait for me!
-Whip!
Hit harder!
Sir, Osman's messengers are here.
Let them in.
Stop this disgrace immediately, Lord.
Release the alps and shahzades.
My castle. My prisoners. I'll
release them only if I want so.
OSMAN BEY KARARGAH
It's tearing my heart out, Osman Bey.
Mehmed... A mountainous warrior...
It's like just yesterday...
He was growing up with me.
While I couldn't even
get used to his growing up,
...this captivity is burning my heart.
You suffering is my suffering, Yakup
Bey. My son Orhan... He is my first child.
He wouldn't even stop
fighting when he was
exhausted. He would
always finish his training.
He's strong... Very strong.
They will stand. They will stand, for sure.
-My Bey.
-But it won't take very long.
Everything will be done to save our sons.
We'll hit the walls and
break the gates if we have to.
And we will take our sons back.
-Is everything set?
-Yes, my Bey.
If we have to be silent, we are
ready for that too, praise be to Allah.
Thank you.
Diggers, huh?
Well-thought, Osman Bey.
They won't be expecting
us to come under the ground.
If they don't release our sons in no time,
...these brave men will
dig both under Kestel...
...and the graves of those dogs.
Let's wait for the alps to bring news first.
I hope we hear our sons are
alive and our hearts stop burning.
You are saying this in case we
have to dig graves for our sons, huh?
They can't dare to do that.
Don't be worrying. There are
many things they'd demand from us.
The agreement depends on you.
Your shahzades turned out to be strong.
But let's see if they can stand this.
Soldiers.
They must be thirsty. I never leave
my prisoners without food and water!
We came here for an agreement, Lord! Release
the shahzades and we'll discuss the terms.
I will kill you.
Negotiating.
If you play by my rules,
of course we can negotiate.
Soldiers, take them away.
Konur Bey, if we
die, it is an honor!
Our name echo around the world. Don't
let these army of dogs what they want.
No sorrow, no grief go
and tell this to our families.
Tell us your rules, our patience grows thin.
Lefka, Karacahisar, Marmaracik
castles. I want all of these castles.
And I want all the tax incomes and
the treasure that these castles have.
We will never give them up!
Think again.
Your decision. If you don't
give them, I will have their heads.
Then we will impale you.
-With your frail arm?
-Yes, with that arm.
Tell Osman Bey and Yakup Bey.
I will come to Lefke to negotiate.
First, you will declare an edict.
After I get edicts and castle keys, I
will release these worthless prisoners.
Whenever I become sure that you kept your
promise, then I will release the prisoners.
You are pushing over the line, lord.
The earlier you send word to
Yakup Bey and Osman Bey..
The lesser prisoners feel pain.
What you see is just the start.
Until you accept my offer,
I will hurt them much more.
Now go.
What do you think they will want, Yakup Bey?
There is nothing more valuable than
your children in this world, Osman Bey.
What they'll want from
me will be within my reach.
Yakup Bey.
Don't let the infidels hear it.
Our children is of course valuable.
-But what you said..
-What are you saying, Osman Bey?
Yakup Bey, there will be a trade in the end.
However, are you willing
to give everything in return?
Of course I will.
However, what they will
get in the end, is death.
What for these swords are forged?
What for these catapults are built?
Even for touching my
son, I will destroy them.
Our children is of course the most valuable.
Of course, there is no doubt,
However, we will not hurry for anything.
Where Turk's foot land is the home to him.
Let us get out of this first.
Since our children is at Kestel..
It means Kestel will be ours soon.
Are you thinking about conquest, even our
when our children are in danger, Osman Bey?
We will take both Kestel, and our sons.
If we take our sons back, then with holy war.
If something happens to
our sons, then with fury.
We will go to them with fury.
My friend Makrenos, I will take back..
All the castles they
got from us. After that..
-I want their lives.
-Will they accept our offer?
All those castles, golds, ores..
Yakup will accept without thinking.
He has a very precious son,
I know. However, Osman..
-Osman will resist.
-What will we do then?
Dividing Yakup and Osman benefits us.
While they mess around, we will be on them.
We can not put a lot of soldiers to Lefke.
\Ne do not need to. The
prisoners we will release..
Why do you think they are bannerless?
They will kill Osman and Yakup.
The Bannerless will kill Osman
and Yakup. Either with easy way..
Or the hard way.
My children.
With each battle they go, my heart burns.
I understand you well, Malhun
Hatun. We are enduring the same pain.
I am standing firm like a rock..
As I am mother of Bey, however,
being a mother is something else.
It is something else.
The son I've raised protected from all evil,
now in the hands of enemy, enduring pain.
O Allah, protect our children. Do
not let merciless have a chance.
Even thinking about it hurts my
heart. This pain is nothing alike.
-It does not indeed. May Allah prevent it.
-Bala.
You don't know what
you eat, what you breathe.
Do not worry, sons are alive,
while there is life, there is hope.
We are the mother of
beys. We will stand straight.
We will stand straight
and unite. We will pray.
There is nothing we can do, Bala Hatun. We
are sitting while they are suffering there.
No, our greatest weapon is our prayer. We
will take refuge to Allah against merciless.
We will pray for every
children that is enduring cruelty.
Alps! Turn against the
wall, take your hats off.
-Will we find the traitor like this?
-We will.
With the permission of Allah, we will.
We will find them, first searching
the ones inside then the outside.
We will. Keep your eyes
peeled, check everyone.
As you command, my shahzade.
We checked the ladies they have no sign.
You continue.
Are you alright? Do you want to take a break?
Do not upset yourself. Mehmet Bey and my
brother are strong. Hopefully they'll be back.
-Do you think so?
-Of course, do not worry.
Come on.
I have a bad feeling, Alaeddin Bey.
Trickster Hatun...
Come, sit... Come.
Stop...
Don't... Don't do this.
You are as strong as your brother.
Don't cry, Trickster Hatun.
You... Aren’t you afraid for your brother?
I am... I am, sure.
But I trust my brother.
Orhan Bey is brave enough to
treat his own dislocated finger.
He will get out of there safely, if Allah permits.
Holofira..
Can he really come out of there safely?
Sure... Besides, you know how much my
brother and Mehmed Bey love each other.
If they unite, no one can harm them.
My Shahzade..
If you allow me, Hatuns.
My Shahzade... We checked all
our Alps. We couldn't find any tracks.
Bayindir Bey. Did you check
the Alps who searched with us?
Since they are all our Alps who
we trust, I couldn't think of that.
Thanks to your mind,
my Shahzade, I will now
question others about
Veysel, Suleyman and Hasan.
The enemy was closer than we thought.
-We cannot trust anyone now, Bayindir Bey.
-Yes my Shahzade.
Come on.
Orhan..
Before he left, he was
going to tell something to me.
I wish I had listened to him. I
wish I had asked for him to speak.
What if he can never
say it? What if he cannot?
Do not say "I wish", Holofira...
With Allah's consent, Orhan Bey
and my brother will come here safely.
Then you will get the answer you want.
Someone is coming!
Are our children alright, Cerkutay?
They are alive, but... I
cannot say they are alright.
What do they want, Konur? Tell us.
Castles, Forts, Marmaracik, Lefke...
Karacahisar, and the taxes
that have been paid until today.
They want the treasure.
They will all be given
with firman and the keys.
Dastard dogs.
-When do they want to meet us?
-Tonight.
-In Lefke.
-Good.
What are you saying Yakup Bey?
Huh? Why would we meet them?
They are asking for the lands and castles
which we took with our swords and blood.
Blood, huh? We have tens of
valiants who can shed blood..
Sword, huh? We can make thousand swords here.
But our children... We
cannot replace them, Osman.
I do not see a difference
between my son and my Alps.
It is also our blood. Do you know how many
fathers lost their children for these lands?
No... We will find a way to take...
...our children back without
giving a single castle. No.
We are not in a situation to make this
careless move. Our children are our priority.
This is the point of no return.
If you give these castles today,
they will have defeated us greatly.
will take courage, they
will even ask for Kutahya.
Stop there, Osman Bey!
Do not overestimate your enemies
and underestimate our power.
I am the Sultan of our
lands! My heart is in pain!
Fortresses and castles will be
given. Our children will be taken back.
My heart is also in pain.
But don't forget, the lands do not belong
to the Sultan, they belong to our people.
Do not fall into that carelessness.
You will make it harder for us
and make them kill our children.
Go to your palace now. First,
find the traitor in your palace.
I will go and meet them alone.
-Kanyumaz!
-My Bey...
-Get ready. We will set out.
-Yes my Bey.
Konur.
-Come on.
-Yes my Bey.
Yakup Bey..
-If you allow me, I want to come with you.
-Come Konur, come.
You will see how I am going
to solve this issue easily.
Alright.
Aykurt...
-You must be hungry.
-Do you think..
..we will eat your food?
Come at me, come!
What is happening here?
You will not give them food ever again.
They should starve, so they can think wisely.
Take these!
Do you think we are going
to be scared and sit still?
You should be afraid of
your own fate, you dogs!
Don’t worry... Soon, I
will send you all to hell.
Are you going to scare
us with death, dastard?
Did you hear him? He is not afraid of death.
If we die, we become
martyrs. But if you die...
...and I will kill you all
with my own hands...
...even jackals will not
want to eat your dead body.
Is that so?
Right.
Dastard dog!
I like you, Orhan.
Come on. We are leaving.
Mehmed Bey and Orhan Bey will
be given in exchange for Karacahisar
Marmaracik and Lefke Castles.
Thankfully. Thankfully, my Rabb.
What are you saying, Cerkutay?
-They are all right, right?
-They are.
They are all right. They will be better
when we take them back from the infidels.
Baysungur. What does
Osman Bey say about this?
This is Yakup Bey's decision.
Osman Bey will obey this decision.
Osman Bey says that...
Saadet Hatun, Osman
Bey will ruin this exchange.
Yakup Bey said that keep
your eyes on the Hatuns.
It is about the life of my
child. I’ll be watching them.
Since we got the blessed
news, let's get back to work.
The palace will be
searched and we will not
stop until we find the
traitor inside. Come on.
My Shahzade, everyone
except Veysel has been searched.
Find Veysel as
soon as possible.
Your dream can only be a mere imagination.
Excuse me?
You're dreaming about
something but that won't work.
They will upset you here a lot
Holofira. They don't value enough.
Sometimes you see right
through me Saadet Hatun.
Motherhood.
Mothers see through their children's eyes.
I loved you at the moment
I saw you as my own child.
I lost my mother when I was so little.
There was no one to replace her.
Then be my daughter-in-law.
And become one of my children.
What's going on Saadet Hatun
is what we're hearing true?
Of course, why would it be wrong? How
can I find a better bride than Holofira?
Son, what happened?
We have captured the traitor
inside the palace, my Valide.
Who is that?
Holofira.
And this is the proof. It was in her room.
Fatma, how could you
think that I'd to such a thing?
What are you saying? Holofira
wouldn't do such a thing.
How could you do this to us?
I didn't do anything.
Sisters! Take Holofira to the dungeon.
Holofira and her helpers will be
questioned. Take them all to the dungeon.
-Come on!
-I didn't do anything.
Malhun Hatun. I wouldn't do
something like this to Orhan.
I said I didn't do it. How could
you think that I did this? Let me go!
What are they trying to do? Even I
know that Holofira wouldn't betray Orhan.
-Doesn't Malhun know that?
-It seems they are after something, mother.
Cerkutay Bey, get the Alps ready.
Yakup Bey is right. They will do
something. Keep your eyes open.
You are wrong. I don't know
where did that cage come from.
Fatma. You need to listen to
me I would never do this to Orhan.
Come on Holofira, come on.
-That cage isn't mine.
-Move.
We know that, Holofira. We
put the cage in your room.
What's going on?
We did it to sneak you out of
the palace. We had no other choice.
We cannot trust anyone
but ourselves. Osman
Bey is waiting for us,
come on, we have no time.
Have a safe journey.
Osman Bey will not just stop,
he'll definitely plan something.
They are so mindless. They'll let my child
die for a few lands. I won't let them do that.
Mother, if they're doing such a move,
there must be a reason that they trust.
What's going on with you Gonca?
What reason are you looking
for? It is clear, they are blinded.
Let's go to the dungeon, come on.
Open the door.
Bala Hatun gave strict
orders. No one will enter.
Don't you know who I
am? I said open the door.
Saadet Hatun.
What are you doing Bala?
My child's life is at stake.
We're doing everything for our children.
You have your son with you, Bala. My son,
the heir of our throne is held by infidels.
While there's peace, I
cannot let you ruin that.
What peace are you
talking about Saadet Hatun?
So many people of ours
were martyred for those castles.
How will we look at them in
the afterlife if we give them away...
Enough, Bala!
Move away, or...
Mother.
Gonca, it is about your brother’s life.
Move away peacefully, otherwise...
Otherwise, what?
This is my palace, Saadet
Hatun, put down your weapons.
Alps! Sisters!
-Bala.
-Arrest them all.
I said Bala!
If my child gets hurt,
-I’ll hurt you.
-Enough.
I said it calmly, but you didn't get it.
We won't talk anymore, you'll wait in
the dungeon until your child returns.
-Come on!
-I won't let you get away with this.
-Take her.
-Let go off me!
I won't let you get away with this, Bala.
When your son comes back, your
anger will cool down, Saadet Hatun.
We're doing this for your good.
-If my son is harmed..
-We should pray...
Saadet Hatun, we should pray
for them to come back safely.
Cerkutay, if it is too hard for you...
It was also hard back then.
And none of you wanted
to make it easy for me.
Open it. Open.
-Let's go somewhere else, brother.
-No.
I don't want. I don't..
I don't want your mercy
that you didn't give me once.
Don't think about me.
Don't you think about me.
You are making a mistake. There
is going back from this, Scholar.
I am Scholar again? Well...
Trickster Hatun, I don't
want you hold you in prison.
But as you are a tricksters
I can only keep you here.
-Alaaddin Bey, if my brothers is harmed...
-Gonca Hatun.
Just trust me. You'll see.
They will be back safely.
I don't believe you anymore, Scholar.
Boran, they are coming.
Make preparations quickly.
As you order, my Bey.
Hurry up, brothers! Come on!
We're going there in these, huh?
Unbelievable! Is this your idea, Gurbuz?
Everyone has different skills, brother.
-We'll conquer the castle with this.
-Just wait, brother.
We won’t go there in barrels this time.
We have a different duty.
You'll be beside the cart with these clothes.
Your skills have gone for nothing, huh?
Osman.
-Osman. Our sons?
-Don't worry.
-We'll take them back.
-I know.
I know but I have a mother's heart, you know.
Malhun, stay strong.
We won't harm the sons.
Don't worry.
I completely trust you.
Holofira, now tell me everything
you know about Kestel.
This matters for Orhan's life.
Osman Bey, Kestel has
three big and two small gates.
One of the big gates is
here. And the other one here.
Two of the small gates are here. And
the other one is under these tunnels.
I think we should go through this gate.
You say all the hidden
passages are known, huh, Aykut?
-For sure, Konur Bey.
-Alright.
Praise be! Praise be!
You took all the measures, Konur.
Well, Yakup Bey. This is
the only the part that you see.
We'll host many heathens, you
know. So we need good measures.
Good. Good. I'll rest until the dark.
Finish all the preparations.
They are going to come,
...take the castles and
citadels and release our sons.
Okay.
Aykut, listen to me carefully.
Keep your eyes wide open.
I'll ask you to do something.
And you'll do exactly what I say.
Find some Christian
soldier clothes for me first.
I will, Konur Bey.
Well, I have heard that...
...The Bannerless are fond of
gold and money. Is that true?
You dog who is afraid
of showing the face off!
We don't draw swords against
Muslims for the belongings of heathens.
Well, gold is simple. When we get
out of here and loot their caravans,
..it will be all ours.
Well, it seems to me that you will
never be able to get out of this dungeon.
You bloody heathens! Leave my brother!
Leave him!
They offered our offer. They
are expecting me in Lefke.
Good. As for you
-The Bannerless.
-Come here.
You and your three men.
You'll go to Lefke with Lord Makronos.
When Osman and Yakup declare their firmans,
..you will be released. Then
in an unexpected moment,
...you will go under their noses.
And you'll stick your dagger into his heart.
Release my brother.
I will release your brothers.
If you do what I say, I will
release your beloved brothers.
This is my offer for you. If
you don't accept, I will kill...
...your beloved brothers
one by one. And it'll be painful!
Enough!Enough. Enough!
Make your choice. Gold and your
brothers or dying in this dark dungeon?
Save your breath for Osman. You will need it.
Stop!
Soldiers, why did you stop us?
Mighty Lord's strict orders.
All the carts will be searched.
What is under this?
Osman Bey...
Put those soldiers in the chests now.
-Here you are, my Bey.
-Here we go.
-Did you find Veysel?
-My Shahzade.
We looked everywhere.
It's like he disappeared.
-Maybe he escaped?
-No.
Every door is locked, he can not escape.
My shahzade, they saw Veysel near alps room.
-Bayindir, quickly.
-Come on.
-Veysel.
-My shahzade.
We are looking for you until
morning, where were you?
My shahzade, I had a duty complete.
Is that so? How long does this duty take?
Do you want something from me, my shahzade?
My shahzade, did I make a
mistake? What is happening?
We will learn what you did.
No marks. Let him go.
My shahzade, what did I do
wrong for you to see me as a traitor?
It is a precaution Veysel.
We are checking everyone.
-No offence, Veysel.
-None taken.
This issue should not divide us,
this precaution is for everyone.
Okay.
Sultan Yakup, it is an
honor to see you in our castle.
Where is Osman Bey?
What do you need Osman Bey for?
You have the Sultan of
Turks. Know your place, lord.
You are talking without weighing,
just because you have our sons.
-Don't test my patience.
-Same goes for you.
Even if you're a Sultan,
pick your words carefully..
Since your heir is in our hands.
The forts and castles you
want will be given to you.
First, we will start with Lefke. Bring it.
I keep my promise, lord.
Now you send word to Kestel.
-They may release the hostages.
-No, Yakup Bey.
It is not that easy.
You will give all the lands.
Then we will deliver your
sons with our soldiers.
Lord.
It is certain that your intention is..
Trading your life in return to all of yours.
If you cross the line one more time.
You can not do anything to us, Yakup Bey.
As we have your son in
our hands we have you too.
Two guards are waiting at the door.
We will handle it quietly. Hasan.
-Scout the area.
-As you command.
-Alps.
-Quickly.
-Osman, what is happening?
-The door is closed, they built a wall.
I didn't know, Osman Bey.
-Do you know any other entrance?
-There is one other way, however..
-It is nearly impossible to get in.
-Tell me where quickly.
Just near the place where
Kestel guards store their weapons.
Quickly, let us go.
May Allah protect our children.
This is the place Osman Bey.
-Boran.
-Bey.
-You know what to do.
-We do, Bey.
Quickly.
They will not notice their
absence. Let us go inside.
Deliver the key of Lefke..
To the lord.
Or, his conditions will be grim.
How did Osman allow this, Sultan Yakup?
Getting these forts and
castles took him years.
Because you don't have
Osman Bey in front of you now.
You have Sultan Yakup in front of you.
These forts and castles that took
Osman to conquer many years..
That gives you the taste of victory..
Is no bigger than my hunting hall.
Also, I am the conqueror of Lefke.
To show that my
intentions are true, soldiers!
We release this many prisoners for Lefke.
When our other requests are
met, your shahzade will be free.
Untie him.
Do not worry, lord. You
will get what you want.
Now, give us the edict that
proves Lefke belongs to us.
Kanyumaz, bring it.
Raise the crusader flags, soldiers.
Yakup Bey is giving Lefke to its real owner.
You will reuinte with your coins and
your family after you finish your duty.
-Is this the place?
-Yes, Osman Bey.
If we pass behind this door, we'll get
to a passage close to the dungeons.
“Thankfully.
-Come on, let's hurry up Alps.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
Hurry up.
Come on.
-Boran.
-My Bey.
-Tell Alps to wait at the passages.
-Okay my Bey.
Ayaz, stop.
-Orhan!
Orhan! Orhan!
Boran! Give me the keys!
-They’re not here my Bey.
-Osman.
Osman, do something, please!
Osman, are you looking for this?
No one can take men without
my permission from this dungeon.
I'll take your head too,
and I'll take my son back.
Orhan, hang on, please.
My Bey.
Orhan, hang on.
Orhan, Orhan!
Orhan, Orhan, what did they do to you son?
-My Bey.
-He's all right, he's all right.
Thankfully you are alive. Thank Allah.
Thankfully he is all right.
Mehmed, Mehmed.
Oh my son.
Mehmed. Mehmed.
Osman Bey.
-You're all right too.
-Thankfully.
-Holofira.
Holofira, untie his legs, come on.
Come on, you're leaving.
-My Bey.
-Gurbuz.
Kestel is up, soldiers are coming.
They'll come for us when they
see there are no soldiers left here.
-Come on, let's go to the hidden passages.
-Come on.
-Come here son, get up.
Get up, come on.
-Boran.
-My Bey.
Throw the fire arrows, we got the boys.
Okay my Bey.
Come on, come on.
Allah is the Greatest!
Hang on, son. Hang on.
Come on Orhan.
Sultan Yakup, you couldn't let your son die.
Your compassion and your
love are your weaknesses.
Believe me, this will be your end.
Wait, Yakup Bey.
Neither crescent loses against the cross
nor our lands can be captured by the enemy.
The deal is broken, Osman Bey went to
Kestel and saved Osman and Mehmed.
It is a lie! You're lying!
We still have Mehmed!
Osman can do anything.
But he never lies. Now, tell me.
Who can save you from me?
Your son survived but you won't!
Don't let him go!
Catch him!
Alps, stop them, don't let them pass.
Lefke will be washed by your
blood Yakup, you will all die!
Yakup Bey, stay behind us.
At such a time
it is not right to stay
behind and hide, Konur.
Attack!
Gonca Hatun.
Scholar?
Any news about my brother?
Why are you here then? To
make fun of my miserable state?
Do you think I have fun with this?
I don't know.
I don't know you anymore, Alaeddin Bey.
You have too many faces.
-And now you're calling me two-faced.
-However you want to understand it.
Say it, why are you here?
You were coughing.
I boiled some herbs. They'll be helpful.
You put me in the dungeon and
then bring me the cure, is that so?
That's what I'm talking about.
-I don't understand you, Alaeddin Bey.
-What about you?
Does everything you do has
a meaning, Trickster Hatun?
Have a blessed night.
If you get some news.
I'll let you know, don't worry.
Lord Makrenos, the hidden passage is here.
Let's go.
Kill them. Search everywhere!
They escaped through the hidden
passage. Go after them, come on!
I'll not stop
until I exterminate the ones
who tried to hurt my son.
My Allah... We have no
one else to ask help from.
My brother is a brave, an honest man.
Protect him, do not test us with his grief.
You are the One Who Protects
You are the One Who Gives...
Let my brother be with us, my Allah.
Aameen.
If you want to support
people who make a
-My Fatma..
-Mother...
My beautiful daughter... Don't cry.
With Allah's consent, your brother will come.
-He will come, right, mother?
-Right.
Didn't you see?
Malhun took Holofira and left.
What else can your brother
do except for coming here?
Really, mother...
After what Holofira did...
..will my mother accept her?
Let's hope so.
What about you? Did you test Gonca?
What do you think? Do you think
she will be a good daughter-in-law?
Look at you... You are
trying to make me speak, huh?
Come on, mother... What do you think?
Gonca is a good girl. She
was raised well, it's obvious.
But... I cannot say the
same thing for Saadet Hatun.
And daughters are raised by their mothers.
I will observe her for
some more time... But...
...we need someone who is
close to her and knows her better.
I have someone in my mind,
but I don't know if she will help us.
Do you mean Ulgen?
-We will part our ways here, Osman Bey.
-Okay.
Now Saadet Hatun is
waiting for us in Yenisehir.
Come with us, so she can be relieved.
If I go there with you, my mother will
not be the only one who will get happy.
Our route leads us to many ways now.
We have friends and enemies...
Let's not make them happy.
As you wish, Mehmet Bey.
But this is not something we should hide.
Everyone will hear it sooner or later.
-It's your decision.
-Thank you Osman Bey.
owe you my life.
When the right time comes,
don't doubt that I'll pay it back.
Thank you.
-May you go safely.
-Thank you.
Come and drink our cold ayran, Mehmet Bey.
-We have common memories now.
-Do not think that we are equal...
...because we were at the same
place and suffered together, Orhan Bey.
Go and drink your ayran
in the face of your father.
You are so arrogant that..
...you are even insulting
the ones who saved your life.
Go now, Mehmet. That day is not today.
Go.
You will learn when that day comes, Orhan.
You will learn. Come on!
We still haven't received any news. I
will question them once I get out of here.
-Bala...
-Open it.
Now you are free, Saadet Hatun.
-Any news from my Mehmed?
-I have good news.
Orhan and Mehmed are safe.
Osman Bey saved them, they are on the way.
-Thanks to Allah!
-Thanks to Allah, mother!
-Bala Hatun...
I came together with my son but...
...I will not forget this impudency.
I will question you about this.
I did everything for our
children, Saadet Hatun.
Let your son come first, hug him...
..then we'll talk about these.
My son knows where to go.
Cerkutay Bey. Prepare
the horses, we are leaving.
May I ruin and destroy
the house of the nafs...
...and may ambition and lust burn with it.
Let me open my hands to pray..
...and fight with my nafs.
-Peace be upon youi, Dervish.
-Peace be upon you too.
What are you doing on
this road with no horse?
I was performing ablution.
Do you think people cannot do
anything on this road without a horse?
Astagfirullah. I did not mean that.
There are many bandits and
sinners (criminals) on this road.
We can accompany you if you wish.
Thank you. We are going a different way.
Considering your wounds, you
have already met those sinners.
You got out of a little fight...
...and now you are trying to
arrive on time for the big fight.
We've been through some
things... Allah knows how small...
...or big it is.
How do you know we are going somewhere?
Come, sit. Have some rest. Let
me offer you something to eat.
So, Dervish Efendi. How do you
know we are going somewhere?
We are not saying it because
we are the ones who know.
Do you know Rasulullah's
(PBUH) expedition of Tabuk?
Peace be upon him.
I do.
It was the expedition in which he
participated with the largest army.
When he returned to Medina after that war...
...he said to his sahabas:
You have come from the
little jihad to the great jihad."
When his sahabas asked, "What
is the great jihad, O Rasulullah?"...
...he said, "The great
jihad is the jihad you wage
against the desires and
ambition of your nafs." .
If you ask what the desires
and ambitions of the nafs are...
...for some it is gold,
for some it is titles...
...some fill it with the
ambition for the chair...
...others fill it with ambition for friends.
Now you're asking...
..."Why is this old
dervish telling me these?"
I'm telling you because the
person in front of me is a human.
Humans have nafs.
Nafs is the total of your ambitions.
We need to learn how to defeat it.
We shall overcome our
nafs(self) and surrender to Allah.
Those surrendering to Allah will find peace.
If you can't peace, you'll
give the leash to your nafs...
...and be a companion of Satan.
Be careful. He would leave
no peace and order in the world.
Although you are wounded, you got out of the
battle and arrived here. It means you won.
If Allah permits,
you will defeat your nafs(self) too.
I should get going now.
Have a safe journey.
Thank you Dervish, Thank you.
Brother!
-My sister.
-Welcome, my Bey.
Thank you.
We got rid of another
trouble, thanks to Allah.
Thanks to Allah.
-Mother.
-Son.
Fatma, just stop.
We saved him from the
heathens. Don't choke him.
Well... I was so scared, father.
Come to me. Come here.
Holofira.
Thank you. You saved us from a huge trouble.
-You acted bravely.
-You're welcome, Osman Bey.
Thank you.
Leave some for us, Fatma Hatun!
Thanks to Allah, brother!
My brother...
Thanks to Allah.
I never doubted you would come.
Well, I just wanted to visit Kestel.
Captivity can do nothing to us. Come here.
Make the preparations.
We're going to the border market.
What are we going to do there, father?
It's not only us who endured the hardships.
Germiyans suffered too.
We'll go say our good wishes.
And show our strength.
-Boran.
-My Bey.
Go ahead and let them know we're coming.
-We'll make a fancy entrance.
-As you order, my Bey.
GERMIYANOGULLARI BORDER - BORDER MARKET
Do I have permission, my Bey?
Mehmed? Come in, son.
What did they do to you, son?
Jackals' mouths watered when
they saw a wolf cub, my Bey.
But I endured their torture.
And I never gave up.
Thanks to Allah.
Thanks to Allah, I'm talking
to you here in our tent.
My brave boy.
-Kanyumaz.
-My Bey.
Send a message to doctors.
Tell them to check my boy's wounds.
As you order, my Bey.
Come. Have a seat.
Tell me everything from the beginning.
They ambushed us suddenly, my Bey.
We had made a plan.
Orhan went in first and then I did.
Alps, stop.
You set your eyes on our
lands and made some games.
But you failed.
It's not easy to invade Turkish lands.
What do you want from me?
Everything you own.
This is the end, Lord. Move!
-You can't get away with this.
-Don't worry about that.
Listen to me carefully.
You'll do whatever I say.
Make a mistake and you die.
Did you hear, Lord?
Keep your eyes wide open. Let's go.
-In the name of Allah, the merciful, the compassionate
-Does it hurt too much?
When I saw you...
...all the pain was gone.
If it makes you look after me,
...I will gladly get
wounds, daughter of Lord.
Do not. Don't.
Don't be wounded again, Orhan.
Your mother was so afraid.
Probably, she was.
While I was leaving, I told
you to get along well with her.
But you did even more...
...and came to save me with my mother, huh?
It seems only my mother was afraid.
You? Weren’t you
afraid, Holofira?
was every afraid that...
...you might die.
So was I.
I was afraid that I might not see...
...these eyes again, Holofira.
-We need to heal your wounds.
-It doesn't hurt.
I told you something while I was leaving.
You said we'd talk when I came back.
You remember?
-Yes?
-Well...
While I was captive,
..I had time to think.
Holofira.
-I am in lo...
-Brother?
Sister.
Mother wants to see you.
She wants to see me?
Go. We'll talk again.
Don't keep her waiting.
She was very afraid for you.
-You had to come just in time, right?
-Mother wanted to see you.
Mother. What could I have done, brother?
What were you saying to Holofira?
Nothing.
-What were you saying?
-You'd tell both mother and father.
Brother!
Mehmed, my dear! My son!
-Mother.
-Are you alright, dear?
-What did you do to you, son?
-I'm good, mother. Don't worry
Their hands with which they hit you
shall break!
-Brother? Brother!
-Sister.
Brother!
Are you alright? I got
worried about you, brother!
-I'm fine, sister.
-He's good.
He's good. Such little wounds...
..can't harm my son.
Fitnat, I made a vow.
Get some animals sacrificed
and hand out meat to people.
Mehmed.
-Do I have permission, my Bey?
-Come in.
-Come in, Orhan.
-Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you too.
Praise be, praise be, praise be!
Thank Allah, for making
us unite in one table again.
-Thank Allah.
My heart was in a cell with my Orhan.
-Now, they are both free, thank Allah.
-Thank Allah.
Thank Allah.
Come on then, In the name of Allah,
the compassionate, the merciful.
-Take it.
-Enjoy the meal.
I am so hungry, take it sister.
When talking with Holofira..
You are never this hun..
Look here. Let my daughter speak.
You are poking her on each side.
What is this?
-Say it.
-My brothers..
Do not do anything.
Right, bey. We do not do anything.
-They do everything I say.
-We do, bey.
-We do.
-They do not have any secrets?
For example..
Affairs of heart.
-I don't know.
-Sister.
-Orhan brother.
-I have it under control, bey.
The girls are ready. If not today..
We will meet them in the future.
Then we would gather the council.
No trouble gathering it, after all.
Right, shahzades?
Of course. Let us gather
the council, dance and enjoy.
Bottoms up, while it is cold.
-Stop it sister.
-It is good for you.
My brothers.
It is good for them of course.
Father.
When will we take vengeance from Kestel.
Very soon.
Bey, where is Konur Bey?
-They did not come back to the palace yet.
-Konur is on duty.
We gave him a duty. However..
The move we will make..
Will divide Yakup Bey and us.
We rescued Mehmed with Orhan.
Instead of being grateful
why would it divide us?
Mehmed Bey is so arrogant, mother.
He may even hold grudge against us..
Instead of being grateful.
It is like his father,
Yakup Bey is no different.
We do not expect gratitude from them.
We do not give them a reason to hold grudge.
However, we will answer them..
Just as how they answered us.
Osman Bey will do more
than he says, it seems.
Doing more than what mad says..
Makes you aim more than what he sees.
You will see what I will do in
the border market as well.
GERMIYANOGULLARI BORDER / BORDER MARKET
You go ahead with sacrificals, hatun.
I am thinking about settling business.
-What business, father?
-We are ready..
To give our lives for this land. However..
They endangered my son's
life for a couple of castles.
It is always because of
their weaknesses, Yakup Bey.
They spend lives for a couple of castles.
They see them as more precious than life.
I also have a business to settle.
They put us in that cell.
What cell, hatun?
They say that they are tricking the traitor.
They humiliated us..
In the first chance they got.
Didn't they tell us after, mother?
My brother got released after as well.
What are you defending, Gonca?
They collected reputation by saving me.
They put you in the cell.
These are all their trickery.
May Allah be my witness, I
will answer to all of this, father.
Your place and your tongue
defends them too much.
Look after your heart in
this Alaeddin issue, Gonca.
Of course, mother. It is duty.
They do good deeds.
Under every sincere move they make..
Is filled with trickery.
They put my family in a cell.
They disobey my order..
And make moves with their own will.
It is time to call them out for it, bey.
We will, son.
Very soon, when they least expect it..
We will be on them.
I told myself not to..
Told myself to forget it..
Do you see the place they
see us fit for, it is prison.
Do you think you would stay
still if they didn't put you in?
Look, Osman Bey rescued both
Mehmed Bey and Orhan Bey.
When will you open your eyes.
O people, gather around.
Cerkutay, what is Boran Bey doing?
I have very important news to tell.
is good news.
There is something, we'll figure it out now.
Leader of Ghazis, the mighty
Bey of the tribe, Osman Bey..
Has rescued Orhan Bey, and
Mehmed Bey, son of Yakup Bey..
From the hands of the infidels.
Cerkutay.
Shut him up.
I'll go.
Boran. What are you doing?
This is Yakup Bey's property.
You can't shout without permission.
We are of the strong voice, who
doesn't think about permissions, Cerkutay.
You knew this as well,
when did you forget it?
Boran, Boran.
Don't make me mad.
You are interrupting my
duty. Get off and be quiet.
Yakup Bey tamed you pretty well, brother.
My brother would come back.
But you became like one of
them by drinking Germiyans' water.
Stop, stop!
A random arrow will hit
you Boran brother, get down.
Come on.
- Peace be upon you!
- Peace be upon you too!
Thank you. Thank you.
Osman Bey.
Oh my child.
Thank you friends.
-Thank you, thank you.
-May Allah bless you.
May Allah bless you too.
-Long live Osman Bey!
-Thank you.
Long live Osman Bey!
And now you’re testing my patience
by gathering people behind you.
If you have any trouble or any bothering
we're always here and
we're ready to do our best.
Thank you.
What's this disgrace, Osman Bey?
So.
Sultan Yakup had some flaws.
And we were fixing them.
What is our flaw?
In Lefke Castle
you saved us from the infidels.
Mashallah! You had
all the world hear about it.
You said "I saved Osman
Bey from the infidels."
Isn't that right, Yakup
Bey? Didn't you say so?
And we attacked Kestel Castle.
We saved your son Mehmed.
Here we are.
But you don't even say a word.
I can see that you keep silent.
You forget pretty quickly, Yakup Bey.
Pretty quickly.
I didn't forget
about it Osman Bey.
I was going to take the boys safe and sound.
You made it complicated. You
put yourself and them in danger.
I left for Lefke too.
But you acted before
me. As if that's not enough
you made the whole world hear about it.
So what, Yakup Bey?
First one to go takes what he wants.
And makes the people hear about it.
Isn't that right, people?
Yes, Osman Bey!
Long live Osman Bey!
Clear the way and drop your weapons.
I'll cut the Lord's head now!
Do what he says.
Sir, are you sure?
I said do it, it is an order!
Go to the wall, turn around and kneel.
Take their guns and arrest the soldiers.
Long live Osman Bey!
Is what we hear true, Sultan Yakup?
You tried to give away Lefke
where my son was martyred
just to save your child?
If it wasn't for Osman
Bey, you were going to let
the infidels get away
with our children's death.
Enough!
Is that true, Yakup Bey?
Tell us the truth!
Look at me.
Don't touch her.
Stay back.
Go away!
Anyone who shuts the righteous
is not from us.
He is not from us, let alone being a Sultan!
Are you rebelling against me, Osman Bey?
In this path which we took
the rule the whole world,
if it was up to you
we were going to lose all of our lands.
My path is not the same as yours.
I acknowledged you as the Sultan
because I thought you'd make holy wars.
I pledged loyalty
thinking that you'd ruin the infidels.
But it seems...
...it seems I was wrong.
You're playing with fire, Osman Bey.
If you rebel against me
I'll destroy you.
I was born into the circle
of fire in these lands.
I fought with many cruel people and infidels.
Yakup Bey.
For sure, in this world...
...there's no one I'm afraid of.
I'm neither cruel...
...nor am I like the people you came across.
I'm the Sultan of all the lands.
If you challenge me...
...you'll find out what fear means.
Thankfully.
Go with Yakup Bey, the castles
will not be enough for them.
Take Aykurt with you.
The game that was set against
Yakup Bey will be broken.
Also, take Lord Makronos as a hostage.
Konur.
Kayi banner will be planted in Kestel.
Yes, my Bey.
Kestel will not be a land
for you, it will be a graveyard.
Your banners will be washed by your blood.
Lord.
You can’t even defend your castle.
Are you going to take
Kestel which we will conquer?
You’ll see it when the day comes.
The screams of your men will deafen you!
Look.
One of our men is equal to
a thousand of your soldiers.
Do your best.
Only thing you are
promised is death. Take him.
-Are you all right?
-Thank you. I'm all right.
You've set me free
and I'll never forget this.
Alright.
Konur Bey. All of the
soldiers have been arrested.
From now on, we have the
control of the castle, praise be to Allah.
Thank you.
Fly Kayi flags on the walls of Kestel.
The cruel will know that
Kestel is our property.
The oppressed will be relieved then.
Yes Konur Bey. Come on valiants.
So, Yakup Bey..
You've been announcing
your sultanate for so long.
You are making everyone
hear about your sultanate.
There is no one who hasn't heard of it.
But we haven't seen you
gain a single victory yet.
The one we call a Sultan..
...must help the oppressed first.
He must share the gold with
his people. But we see that...
...we are the ones who are giving the gold.
The one we call a Sultan must conquer lands.
But..
...we are the ones who are doing it.
Yakup Bey...
O, people!
Kestel castle where our
children were taken captive...
...is now the property of Kayi!
Now tell me Yakup Bey.
Are you the Sultan here...
...am I the Sultan here?
You pledged allegiance, Osman.
I am taking it back now.
Where are you Tesellius?
Where are you?
Thomas... Tell our brothers to get ready.
When Makranos takes the castles...
...we will take Sogut.
Tesellius.
-Where have you been Tesellius?
-Sir, Osman...
-Speak, Tesellius.
-Osman took the prisoners.
The castles... They
didn't give those castles.
Yakup is also alive.
Unfortunately we failed sir.
Holy Jesus... Holy Jesus...
I swear, I swear, I swear...
I swear, I will kill them!
Holy Jesus! I am taking an oath before you...
...I will send Osman to
the deepest place in hell!
This is not failure!
This is the last fire Osman
left in us before we kill him!
The last!
Master Gera..
-Did what I thought happen?
-Everything...
...went wrong, Vasilis!
Everything!
Osman saved Orhan and Mehmet.
Yakup is alive! You...
..how couldn't you notice this game?
I did... I noticed something was happening...
You noticed!
But they were looking for the
traitor. I couldn't do anything...
If I did, they could have captured me.
Then why did you come?
Won't they notice your
absence? Why did you come?
Won't they doubt about you now?
-Huh?
-No, they won't.
Because my position in the
palace is even stronger now.
It happened just the way
we predicted, Master Gera.
They checked my back when
they were looking for the traitor.
And they couldn't see a mark.
Vasilis...
You are so valuable.
Their trust in you is great.
Their trust in you will bring their end.
What will be our next move, Master Gera?
We will play such a game...
...to Osman and Yakup that...
...they won't hesitate making an agreement...
...with the devil to kill each other.
Now listen to me carefully.
You pledged allegience, Osman.
Now I am taking it back.
You can be anyone's Sultan
now but you are not my Sultan.
You are not Kayi's Sultan.
You can never be my people's Sultan either!
If you want to see us..
...do not look beside or behind you,
look at who is standing against you!
From now on..
...we are rivals, Yakup Bey.
You have made this rebellion so openly...
...who will save you from my hands now?
I will destroy you in such a way that...
..no one will remember...
...that there was a man named Osman.
We will see.
We will see, Yakup Bey. Who knows...
...maybe the whole world will hear our name.
They will be afraid.
They will shake from fear.
Maybe... we will live on these
lands for hundreds of years.
But fate... Fate...
Only Allah...
Only Allah knows that.